I'll kill the bastard who ordered them to do this—Kida Masaomi!
それを命令したっつう 紀田正臣って野郎をぶっ殺す！
Those are the eyes of someone who's prepared to die.
コレから 死ぬ覚悟した人の目
Do you mean that Horada?
あのホラダって どのホラダだ？
What Horada?
I thought I should tell you what he's thinking.
あの人が何を考えてるのか 伝えたいと思って
I'm also prepared to kill someone.
オレは殺す覚悟をしてきたんだよ
I won't let anyone contradict that!
それは誰にも否定させねぇ！
Are you prepared to accept what you're
about to see, no matter how horrible it may be?
どんな嫌な光景でも受け入れる覚悟はあるな？
Kida!
紀田君！
Why...?
どうして？
Masaomi...?
正臣…
Mikado...!
帝人？
Ryugamine...?
竜ヶ峰君… どうして？
Why...?
This is definitely about as bad as it gets.
確かに これは最悪の光景だよ
So, the black biker shows herself!
出やがったな 黒バイク
お前ら こいつら全員 砂にしちまえ！
Guys, turn all these losers into dust!
Now! Turn on them!
今だ 裏切れ！
You bastard!
Hey, what's going on?
なんだよ？何なんだよ こりゃあ!
What the hell is this?!
You piece of shit!
くそが！
Yo.
Ka-Ka-Kadota!
かっ かっ… 門田ぁ！
Wh-Why you...!
て… てめぇ～！
If you tricked someone with this disguise, then
you should have been wary about adding new people.
この程度の変装で ごまかせるんだから
なまじ人数を増やすのも考えもんだなぁ？
Kadota...
門田さん… これ 一体…
Just what's...
Well, Togusa gave me this idea:
いや 渡草に言われて 思い出したんだよ
when Izumii got arrested, a guy named
Horada was the only one to get away scot-free.
泉井がパクられたとき
てめぇだけうまく逃げ延びて 不起訴になった法螺田ってヤツがいたっけなぁってな
Then he rounded up about thirty of his friends, had everyone throw on some yellow, and they all snuck into your gang.
それで ちょっくら仲間を３０人ほど集めて
適当に黄色い布を着けて 潜り込んだ
Although I left Yumasaki and Karisawa
behind, since they're easily recognizable.
遊馬崎と狩沢は目立つから 置いてきたけどな
So, we don't get to help out at all?
オレたちの出番はないんっすかね
Well, we are easily recognizable.
目立ちすぎるのも考えもんだね
I didn't want to remember anything about you.
てめぇのことなんざ 思い出したくもなかったぜ
You're just that despicable.
あまりに胸くそ悪くてな
Are you the one who broke Saki's leg?
沙樹の足を折ったのは お前か？
N-No...I...
い… いや オレは…
Are you the one who made Saki cry?!
沙樹を泣かせたのは お前か？
My gun... Where's my gun?!
ちくしょう！ チャ… チャカ チャカはどこだ～!
So it was you!
お前だな!
Damn you!
ちくしょ～～！
I was planning on breaking your skull open with that crowbar...
本当はバールで脳天たたき割るつもりだったんだぜ
Mikado and Anri don't belong in this type of world.
帝人と杏里はこっち側の人間じゃないだろ
So there's no reason for them to see a corpse.
だから 死体なんざ見る必要はねぇ そう思っただけさ…
That's what I think...
Masaomi!
正臣！
正臣… 正臣しっかりしてよ！
Hang in there, Masaomi!
Kida!
紀田君！
Celty told me all about your and Sonohara's identities.
園原さんや正臣のこと セルティさんから聞いたんだ
I'm sorry, I...
ごめん 僕… 僕なんにも知らなくて…
I had no idea...
Ryugamine, I...
竜ヶ峰君 私…
You don't have to say anything. I get the gist of it.
言わなくていいよ なんとなく事情は分かったから
So, don't force yourself to say anything.
だから 無理に言わないで
It probably wouldn't have turned out like this if I'd just talked to you guys about what I was suffering through and worrying over.
僕が何に苦しんで 何に悩んでたのか話してれば
こんなことにはならなかったかもしれないのに…
I also felt like you were pulling away from me...
オレこそ…
なんか お前が遠くなっちまいそうで… だから怖くて…
I was so scared...
Masaomi...
正臣…
It's my fault!
私が悪かったんです 竜ヶ峰君にも 紀田君にも 自分のこと話せなくて…
I couldn't tell either of you about myself...
Sonohara...
園原さん…
I'm sorry.
ごめんなさい 私 二人のこと とても大切に思ってたのに…
Even though you're both very important to me...
...and I've always been so close to you...
ずっと近くにいたのに…
You guys are absolutely perfect for each other.
お前ら えらくお似合いだぜ
Masaomi...
正臣…
Hey, can I ask a favor of you if you're going to take me to a hospital?
なあ 病院に運ぶなら 一つだけ頼まれちゃくれねぇかな？
何？
What?
Take me to Raira General. I have a girl who's waiting for me there.
運ぶのは 来良総合病院にしてくれ
待ってる女がいるんだ 頼むよ…
I'm counting on you...
Masaomi?
正臣! 正臣！ 正臣！
Masaomi?!
He looks awful.
ひでぇ有様だな
Kadota...!
門田さん…
Man, I told him not to run away, but this time
he did too good a job of facing things head-on.
ったく 逃げるなとは言ったが
逃げなさすぎだ
He needs to know what a happy medium is.
ちったぁ加減しろよ
So, are these people...?
あの人たちって もしかして…
Yeah, they're all in the Dollars.
ああ あいつら みんなダラーズだ
There are certain things you can do when you don't have a color.
色がねぇからできることがある
Even if you tell them to disappear, they are who they are, so there's no way they can.
消えるって言われてもなぁ
初めっからそういうもんなのに 今更消えようがねぇってことだよな
Hey, Horada's getting away!
おい 法螺田が逃げるぞ！
This way, Horada.
法螺田さん こっちっす
That bastard...
あの野郎！
I'll go after them.
Take Kida to the hospital.
Okay, got it!
ああ 分かった
I have a van parked out front.
表にバンが止めてある 渡草 頼む！
Togusa, I'm counting on you!
Okay!
I've got something to clean up. I'll leave Kida to you.
オレは後片づけがあるんでな 紀田を頼むぞ
What's wrong?
どうしたの？
No, it's nothing.
いえ なんでもないんです
Horada, Higa's not here!
法螺田さん 比賀がいないっす！
Leave him!
ほっとけ！
Sh-Sh-Sh-She's here!
き… 来やがったぁ！ 黒バイクだぁ！
I-I-It's the black biker!
Shut up!
黙ってろ！
What are we going to do, Horada?
法螺田さん これからどうするんですか!
For now, we're going to run away.
とにかく逃げろ！ どっかにトンズラして ほとぼり冷まして…
We'll escape somewhere and wait until things cool down...
Then, once Izumii gets out of the pen, it'll be payback time!
あとは泉井さんがムショから出てくりゃ なんとでも巻き返しできらぁ！
Horada, in front of us! In front of us!
ほ… 法螺田さん 前！ 前！
In front?
前？
Th-That's...Shizuo!
あ… あいつ
静雄！平和島静雄っすよ！
That's Heiwajima Shizuo!
He's alive?!
生きていやがったのか! あれ？
Um, why's there a street sign in the middle of the road?
でも あんな所になんで標識が？
How is he still alive? How?!
なんで生きてんだよ？ なんで…
Horada!
法螺田さん！
Hey...
おらぁ～！
You won't get away!
逃げてんじゃねぇ～～!!
Pull yourself together, Horada!
法螺田さん しっかりしてください！
Th-The black biker!
くっ 黒バイク！
Calm down, Horada!
You've got some nerve, coming that close to a police bike.
警告前の白バイに幅寄せかますたぁ いい度胸だ
Don't underestimate traffic cops, you brats.
交機をなめるなよ ガキども
Horada and the others were arrested.
法螺田たちは逮捕された
I heard they claimed that Heiwajima Shizuo
destroyed their car, but their words fell upon deaf ears.
平和島静雄に車を破壊されたと 訴えたそうだけど
警察は聞く耳を持たなかったらしい
Take care of him.
お大事に
Thank you for everything.
ありがとうございました
Huh?
あれ？ 園原さんは…
Where's Sonohara?
That's it all right.
うん 間違いない
Now I can finally get that reward from the Awakusu Association.
確かに受け取ったよ
これで やっと粟楠会から報酬がもらえる
Okay. However, I couldn't retrieve the bullets...
うっす 弾までは回収できなかったですけど
Well, that's fine.
いいの いいの
I would've been lucky if you'd killed Shizu-chan with this.
まあ これでシズちゃんが殺せたら ラッキーだったんだけどね
So, you used me to give Horada that information about Shizuo?
それで オレ通じて 法螺田に静雄の情報流したんですね
He would've died if you'd hit him in either the head or the heart.
せめて頭か心臓を撃ってくれれば 死んだかもしれないのに
How disappointing.
本当に残念だよ
And that's how it is, Mother.
そういうことらしいです 「母さん」
Huh?
Um...Thank you very much.
あの… ありがとうございます
Now go home and live a normal life.
あとは家に帰って 普通に暮らしてください
Um...so you're Orihara Izaya?
あの… あなたが折原臨也さんですね？
Oh, you're Sonohara Anri?
ああ 園原杏里ちゃん？
Or should I say Saika?
いや 罪歌って呼んだ方がいいのかな？
What do you want at this late hour?
こんな時間になんの用？
You're going to let me slash you.
あなたのことを斬らせてもらいます
Oh?
Why? Why have you done this?
どうして… どうしてこんなことをしたんですか？
I haven't really done anything.
オレは別に何もしてないよ
Well, if I had to give a reason for my
actions, I guess it's because I love people.
そうだねぇ あえてその行為に理由を付けるとするなら
好きだからかなぁ 人間が
I guess I wanted to see the many faces that mankind has to offer.
だから オレは人間のいろいろな面が見たかったのかもしれないね
Question time!
さて問題です 今の答えは本当でしょうか？ うそでしょうか？
Was my answer just now the truth or a lie?
I'll know...once I gain control of you.
あなたを支配すれば分かりますから
By the way, what about you?
ところで 君はどうなんだい？
If you truly want to lead a happy, peaceful life, shouldn't you just slash everyone you know?
本当に平穏で幸せな毎日を手に入れたいなら
その刀ですべての知り合いを斬ってしまえばいいじゃないか
That's...
そんなのは… そんなのは違います！
That's not the answer!
Well then, can you say that it's right to not make your feelings for either Mikado or Kida clear, despite knowing they're both attracted to you?
おやおや それなら 帝人君と正臣君
どちらからも好意を寄せられながら
Don't you just use your belief that you can't love others as an excuse to complacently accept how things are?
いまだ答えをはっきりさせない 君の態度は果たして正解と言えるかい？
Aren't you just using your assumption that you can't love others as an excuse to be complacent with how things currently are?
君は自分が人を愛せないと思い込んで
それを理由に今の立場に満足してるだけじゃないか？
Saika loves people in your stead?
罪歌が君の代わりに人間を愛してくれる？ バカバカしい
Don't be ridiculous—
Just shut up!
黙ってください！
You know...
あのさ あんまり軽く見てもらっちゃ困るね
You shouldn't underestimate me.
I mean, it's not like I got to be Shizu-chan's rival by just pretending to fight with him.
オレだって だてにシズちゃんとケンカして 張り合えるわけじゃないんだよ
At the very least...
それと
You shouldn't have given this to me.
せめてこれをオレに渡すべきじゃなかったね
I'll tell you right now that I won't use it on you.
言っておくけど 君は狙わないよ
Just whom should I use it on?
誰にしようかな そこら辺を歩いてるカップルとか？
How about that couple walking by over there?
It shouldn't cause you too much emotional pain, since you can't love others.
君は人を愛せないんだから 大して心は痛まないかな
I'd known for a long time that Higa had fallen victim to the Slasher.
比賀君が 斬り裂き魔事件の被害者だなんてことはとっくに知っていたよ
Why do you think I told him to get this gun back for me?
なんでそんな彼に今回の拳銃回収を命じたと思う？
Because of you.
君だよ 君に宣戦布告したかったからさ
I wanted to declare war on you.
I deeply love people, too.
僕も人間を深く愛しているんだ
Like I'd ever hand them over to some sword.
刀ごときに人間を渡してたまるか
People are my playthings.
人間はオレのもんなんだからさ
Oh, but you can have Shizu-chan; I don't need him.
ああ でも シズちゃんだけはいらないから くれてやるよ
I'm praying for you to cut him up like a fish as soon as possible.
なるべく早くなます斬りにすることを祈ってるから
Good luck!
頑張ってね それじゃ！
See you!
You're late.
遅かったわね
What's up with your face?
何？ その顔 どうしたの？
What happened?
I got hit with a pretty good punch.
ちょっと いいパンチをくらってね
Hey!
Huh?
Simon?
サイモン？
Hey, I have something to tell you, but you're not going to like it.
You're so cowardly it's funny.
Yeah...I know I'm a coward.
But, Simon...
I love my own cowardice.
Do you remember Masaomi's girlfriend? She called my store.
She told us all about you and what you're doing.
Saki did?
Why would she...?
Because she's truly in love with Masaomi.
It looks like she's turned her back on you.
I see... Saki, huh...
Hey, Izaya...
Don't ransack this town too much.
Simon, I told you I truly love people.
Don't try to trick me with that logic.
In reality, you just don't want to lose to Shizuo, right?
You just have a Shizuo complex, don't you?
You don't realize just how much those around you can tell what you're thinking.
...Simon,
You seem like a totally different person when you're speaking Russian.
お前 ロシア語と日本語で 印象変わりすぎだって
Hey, can I ask you something?
なあ 一つ聞いていいか？
What?
何よ？
You're the one who told Horada about Mikado, right?
法螺田に帝人君の情報流したのって 君だろ？
I wonder...
どうかしらね
Vindictive people like you are just scary.
怖いねぇ いまだに根に持ってるとは
Geez...whenever someone reacts exactly the way I expect them to,
まったく… オレの予想どおり動いてくれる人もいれば
there are always people like Shizuo and Simon
who turn those expectations on their heads.
サイモンや シズちゃんみたいに予想を覆す人間もいる
That's why I'll never ever stop loving people.
だからこそ オレは人を愛して愛して愛してやまない
ああ そうさ！ だからきっとこんなクソッタレな仕事を続けていられるんだろうねぇ
That's it!
That's definitely how I'm able to keep working this piece of shit job.
ヘドが出るぐらいに楽しいよ
It's so fun it makes me vomit.
I'll say it again, but I'm pretty sure that humanity hates you.
何度も言うけど 人間の方はたぶんあなたのことが大嫌いよ
Probably...
そうかな？
Sa...
沙…
I know.
知ってるよ 正臣 ほんとは来なかったんでしょ
You never came, did you, Masaomi?
You just kept calling Izaya, didn't you?
正臣 ずっと臨也さんに電話掛けてたんでしょ
Again and again...
何回も 何回も
Izaya laughed as he showed me his phone's incoming call history.
臨也さん笑いながら着信履歴見せてくれた
But you don't need to worry about it.
でも 気にすることないよ
Even if you had come, not much would've changed.
あの後来られても 私としては大して変わんないし
Stop it...
やめてくれ…
Then at least you didn't get injured...
だったら 正臣がケガしなくて それがいちばんよかったって…
Let's break up!
別れよう！
Let's break up...
別れよう…
I'm horrible...
最低だな オレ
What did Saki ever see in me?
沙樹はオレのどこを見てかっこいいなんて思ったんだろうな
The fact that you're oddly obedient.
その変に素直なところよ
How long have you been here?
いつからいたんだ？
Not long.
さっき 狩沢さんたちから聞いたよ 全部
Karisawa and the others told me everything.
You're a fool.
バカだね 正臣は本当にバカだよ
You really are a fool, Masaomi.
You've known that for a long time.
分かってるだろ 昔から
Um, there's something I have to apologize for.
あのね 謝らなきゃいけないことがあるの
Actually, I got caught by those people on purpose.
本当は私わざとあの人たちに捕まったの
Izaya told me it'd all stop if I did.
それで全部終わるって 臨也さんが言ってたから
That's why that night...
だから 私自分で… 自分であの夜 あのたまり場に…
That night, I went by myself to their meeting place...
And afterwards, Izaya told people about it...
それで あとは臨也さんが情報を流して…
I know.
知ってたよ 臨也のヤツに言われたんだろ？
He told you to, didn't he?
He told you to keep pretending you couldn't walk so he could reign me in.
オレを引き止めるために ずっと歩けない振りをしろって…
He probably wanted to turn me into his pawn.
オレを手駒にしたかったんだろうな
Masaomi...
正臣…
I have ESP, you know.
オレ エスパーだもんよ
This is the first time I've ever disobeyed him.
初めて臨也さんの言うことに逆らっちゃった
I think I can finally say it.
今ならやっと言えそうな気がする
I couldn't come save you.
助けに行けなかった ごめん
I'm sorry.
But, I still love you.
だけど オレはやっぱり沙樹のことが好きだ
So, please, don't break up with me.
だから 頼む 別れないでくれ
Hey...
You really are a fool, Masaomi.
やっぱり正臣はバカだよ 本当のバカだよ
You're an absolute idiot.
I can't help it.
しかたねぇだろ 欠点の一つぐらい 目ぇつぶってくれ
Can't you close your eyes to at least one of my faults?
If you know you have one, then fix it.
自分で分かってるなら 直そうよ
We'll fix it together.
一緒に直していこうよ
A few days later, Masaomi disappeared along with Mikajima Saki.
数日後 正臣は三ヶ島沙樹とともに姿を消した
They notified the school that they were dropping out and just disappeared.
学校に退学届を出し 僕らの前からいなくなった
Everyday life changed for the three of us that had been living together.
いつも三人だった僕らの日常は変わってしまった
And yet, the city hasn't changed at all.
けど 街はいつもと変わらない
Russia Sushi!
Neither has he,
彼も 彼らも
Ready, go!
nor have they,
or them,
彼らも 彼も
or him,
彼も
It's so tranquil.
平和だな
Yeah.
うん ブルースクウェアの残党の間でも
いろいろ内部分裂があったみたいで
Apparently there's internal strife even amongst the remaining people from the Blue Squares,
and the Yellow Scarves have also quieted down a lot.
黄巾賊もだいぶおとなしくなってるらしいよ
I see. Then there's no reason to worry about anyone coming after Anri or Mikado for the time being.
そうか じゃあ とりあえず 帝人や杏里ちゃんが狙われる心配はないんだな
Eh?
Wai... What's with that bold change of clothes?
ちょっ… 何？ その大胆な衣がえ
If you're going to provoke me like that, I've got to take a shower and prepare some bed sheets.
そんな挑発されたら 僕もう ちょっとシャワー浴びてきて ベッドのシーツを整え…
Huh?
What's wrong?
どうした？
Well, usually you'd give me a Hell Stab
somewhere around here or pinch my cheek.
いや いつもなら このへんで地獄突きされたり ほおをつねったりしてくるからさ
I actually am trying to provoke you.
実際挑発してるんだよ
Or even them.
そして 彼らも
We'll never regain the everyday life that we've lost, will we?
失われた日常は もう 僕らには戻ってこないのだろうか？
I wonder if I loved Kida...
紀田君のこと 好きだったのかな？ 私
Is that why I feel so lonely?
だから こんなにさみしいのかな？
But, I don't know.
でも分からないんです 私 そういうのよく分からないから
I don't really...understand that stuff.
There is one thing I understood.
一つ分かったことがある ダラーズは街だ
The Dollars are this city.
Various people come and go, without being dyed a certain color.
いろいろな人がやってきては 去っていく
There's always something happening.
一つの色に染まらず
There are always people hating and loving each other, cultivating friendships, and passing others by.
いつも何かが起こっている
誰かと誰かが憎しみ合い 愛し合い
友情を育て すれ違っている
Just like a city will continue to exist as long as there are people around, the Dollars will also continue to exist.
人がいるかぎり 街が存在し続けるように
ダラーズもまた存在し続けるんだ
No matter what anyone says.
誰かの意思とは無関係に
Good Evening.
'Evening.
Oh, we have a new person, I see.
Hello,
nice to meet you. I'm Bacula.
Kanra invited me to join!
Huh, I met him through the Internet, but did you as well, Bacula?
No, we know each other from RL.
We're like business partners!
At least that's the front we put up...
Kya!
When are you going to die, Kanra?
That's a harsher quip than I expected!
That's horrible.
Sorry,
Kanra was being really annoying,
So I just...
Um, Bacula,
please excuse me if I'm wrong.
Are you Masaomi?
Is that you, Masaomi?
It...It'd be great if you'd just say something.
You've met me in RL, so please tell
everyone what's so charming about me.
The square root of three points.
Huh?
If I were to express your charm with points,
it'd be the square root of three points.
So, in other words, I'm so beautiful that you can't evenly divide me?
More like you're too difficult for elementary
school kids, so we shouldn't show you to them.
Oh, sorry,
this is it for me today.
Okay.
See you.
Good night.
Um, Bacula!
Please come again!
You're always welcome!
I'll be back. See you!
'Night.
Good Night!
Bacula has left the chat room.
A place to come home to and an everyday life that's been lost...
帰るべき場所 失った日常
それは確かにネットの中にも存在していた
...also exists on the Internet.
He'll come back.
戻ってくるよ
Eh?
正臣は絶対に戻ってくる
Masaomi will definitely come back.
So, let's give him crap when he does.
だから そのときは文句を言ってやろう
Let's pretend to be really mad at him as a joke!
笑いながら 本気で怒ってやろうよ
Both of us will do it together.
二人で一緒に ですよ
I still think it's mysterious even now...
今思っても不思議だけれど でも
...but I also get the feeling it's not.
なんだかそれは僕の人生が変わってしまうようなことで
Anyway, it was something that changed my life.
And yet, it seems like nothing's changed at all.
実は何一つ変わっていないような
It was something very, very strange,
とても とても奇妙で けれど どこにでもある経験をした
and, at the same time, something everyone experiences.
It all happened here in Ikebukuro.
この池袋の街で
制作：lastzzz akira 安静の云
漫游字幕组
http://popgo.net/bbs